Animesh Shrivastava

Male, Married, Born: July 9th, 1979

Mob: +91-9886244329 Email-id: ani979@gmail.com

Address: 7D, 3rd Block, Alps Estate, Kaikondarahalli, Off Sarjapur road, Bangalore – 560035

Objective

I am having eleven years of experience in IT Industry. These eleven years comprises of 6 years in a development role and almost 5 years of technical as well as managerial & leadership exposure. The current domain which i am involved in is Set Top Boxes. On this domain I have worked for eight years.

I see myself as a lead/manager in the organization i will be joining in without compromising on my technical expertise. My main objective is to keep learning and utilizing it for the growth of the organization.

Technology Exposure

Languages: Core Java (Algorithms, Data structures, Multithreading), Design Patterns

Methodologies: Agile(Scrum + Extreme Programming), Continuous Integration (CruiseControl)

Version Control: CVS, Clearcase(UCM), CM Synergy

Exposure to Tools: JIRA, Confluence, Jenkins, Cruisecontrol

Domain Exposure

Currently working in the SetTopBox domain. In this domain from past 9 years.

Work Experience: (11 years)

 CISCO Video Technologies Pvt. Ltd. (16th May 2005 till date) (Previously known as NDS Ltd.)

Current Designation: MANAGER.ENGINEERING(40 Technical: 60 Managerial)(Team size: 11)

Role at Cisco: Leading a team and a component of the product software stack. Leading two different teams from the same customer.

Key Responsibilities:

- **Technical responsibilities**: Development (debugging mostly), Code Reviews, design reviews, requirement reviews, impact analysis, automation tests (Unitary tests, Functional tests), managing Jenkins.
- Management responsibilities: Appraisals, hiring, team motivation, supporting scrum teams, continuous feedback, rewards and recognitions.

Current and important pervious project(s):

KDG/Vodafone (Client: KDG Gmbh, Germany) About Project:

KDG is a one of the biggest broadcaster in Germany and has been acquired by Vodafone presently. The project deals with the cable delivery system on both DVR and Zapper boxes. I am currently the UI component lead for the project. My daily work involves leading the component roadmap and regular coordination with NDS France office for project management discussions. I am working for this project from past 4 years. **Technical Expertise:** JAVA 1.4, CM Synergy, Agile methodology.

2. DirecTV (Client: DirecTV USA)

About Project:

DirecTV is one of the biggest satellite delivery broadcaster in US. Cisco has provided an end to end solution to DirecTV for their DVR as well HD Zapper boxes. I have been worked for a DVR project, R15. The work mainly involved the support and maintenance of this project. This included change request management along with support for their deliveries.

Technical Expertise: JAVA CLDC 1.0 compliant, Clearcase UCM, DSS(APG), Continuous Integration(CruiseControl)

Integral India Software Development Centre (July 2004-May 2005) (100% Technical)

Integral is a software development organization delivering forex related products to its various customers which includes CITI, Barclays, Bank of America......

SRA India (June 2003-July 2004) (100% Technical)

A sister concern of Software Research Associates Inc organization Japan, SRA India development centre developed software for its clients mostly in Japan. I was involved in two such projects.

Academic Qualifications		
Degree	Year	Institution
B.E (Information Technology), 70% Agg.	2002	Dr. AIT, Bangalore (VTU University)
Class XII	1998	DAV Senior Secondary , Chandigarh
Class X	1996	St. Joseph's School, Bhagalpur